<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://longnguyen1997.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 02:49:51 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 02:49:51 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>my time in Korea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;warning: this is a particularly long post. activate your browser’s Reading Mode (if it has one) for a more pleasant time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity&quot;&gt;opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this summer, I had the pleasure of working at the Electronics &amp;amp; Telecommunications Institute of Korea (ETRI, or 한국전자통신연구원 in Korean), courtesy of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://misti.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;MIT International Science and Technology Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. working down the hierarchy, we go from ETRI to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etri.re.kr/eng/sub6/sub6_01020102.etri;jsessionid=061E58886E8372E2F7F340AC2801A1A5?departCode=101&amp;amp;departInfoCode=191&quot;&gt;Software Contents Research Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, from there to the Intelligent Robotics Research Division, from there to the Human-Machine Interaction Research Group, and from there to my desk. at the head of the HMI Research Group is 박재홍, and my mentor for the summer was 윤영우. there really should be honorifics, but for the sake of blogging, let’s just consider names as names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project&quot;&gt;project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as part of the HMI Research Group (which I will defer to HMIRG henceforth), my responsibility as an intern was to investigate &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis&quot;&gt;sentiment analysis&lt;/a&gt; and natural behavior in physical robotics. I was given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ald.softbankrobotics.com/en/robots/nao&quot;&gt;NAO robot&lt;/a&gt; to work with. the current state of robotics movement leaves much to be desired—we don’t have many robots that can actually generate realistic gestures in realtime as they speak. instead, what many manufacturers opt for are predefined gestures replicated from short video clips—in NAO’s case, coded by hand in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/code&gt; format&lt;/a&gt;. these gestures are rather repetitive and predictable. do humans move their head with identical spatial, temporal parameters every time they express agreement to something? didn’t think so! by using machine learning, statistics (which itself is a crucial part of ML), and natural language processing, we can train robots to better respond in an organic way during real interactions with real people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;having come in with &lt;em&gt;zero&lt;/em&gt; NLP/ML experience, I found myself daunted during the initial stages. I quickly caught up on theory, thanks to MIT’s 6.036 Spring 2015 notes, acquainting myself with the ML library &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn&lt;/code&gt; and the NLP libraries &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;spaCy&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nltk&lt;/code&gt;. I learned quite a lot, and though there were some dull moments during the project that involved tedious tasks like collecting robot sensor data, I loved doing what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language-barrier-the-greatest-challenge&quot;&gt;language barrier: the greatest challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I speak for a lot of people when I say that the biggest problem living and working in Korea was the language barrier. despite having studied Korean for two years at MIT, I found myself lost the moment I set foot in Korea. four semesters—not quite enough. I now realize that I haven’t even crossed the barrier between &lt;em&gt;beginning&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;comfortable&lt;/em&gt; yet. a big help was that fact that the Korean, Japanese, and Vietnamese languages are heavily Sinicized (influenced by Chinese culture). over 60% of these languages are derived from Chinese characters; in my case, Vietnamese derives from Hán tự, while Korean derives from 한자. so many words are the same, with only minute differences in pronunciation. this made a lot of new vocabulary words pretty trivial and engrained the moment I saw them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bottom line: I was required to adapt. I chose Daejeon over Seoul for complete immersion. I think I can count on one hand the number of times I saw foreigners in Daejeon during my almost-3-month stay. signs in Korean were everywhere, and my ears were, at any given moment, ready to burst from the amount of information cramming itself into their canals. it speaks volumes that my reading speed is at least three times as fast as it was before I arrived (and that’s after two years of studying the language formally). I can now think of what to say next as my brain quickly processes Korean grammar rules and strings together phrases accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can expose yourself to any language for years and years through formal courses and television, but your rate of growth is &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much more pronounced when you’re actually in an environment that allows breathing room for &lt;em&gt;only that language&lt;/em&gt;. for those of you looking to come to South Korea, do yourself a favor and don’t rely on your English to get you around. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work-culture-in-a-foreign-country&quot;&gt;work culture in a foreign country&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because I was at a research institute, I can’t say for certain that my experience accurately describes that of those in industry. for the most part, it’s pretty similar to the US, with a few differences. first, you’re expected to come in at 9:00, leaving at 18:00 with an hour-long lunch break. Koreans are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; punctual and work-oriented: one of the senior researchers in my lab lives about a $25 taxi ride away, yet was always at his desk by around 8:30. as far as I know, most people in the Bay Area working at software companies are free to come around 10-11 and leave pretty early in the afternoon, granted their work is solid. definitely a difference. second, greetings and etiquette are emphasized more heavily in Korea. once, one of the project leaders scolded me for not saying hello to every member of the lab when I came in. it was terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we also practiced the standard Korean tradition of 회식 (hweh-shik), which involves nights of debauchery with dozens of beer bottles and comfortable conversation in the company of one’s colleagues. I’m a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good drinker, so this was no problem, and more importantly, these nights reminded me a lot of good times back in Cambridge with my friends. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/news/biz/2016/04/328_139616.html&quot;&gt;Korea being a workaholic country&lt;/a&gt; is no joke, but it’s traditions like these that, understandably, sway your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;had I stayed in the US for an internship, I wouldn’t have grown so much. all summer, work felt secondary next to the cultural nuances, the unpredictable weather that is the annual 장마, the language exchanges during which I spoke in Korean and the other interns spoke in Korean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also, did I mention that I was the youngest in the lab by at least four years to everyone else? I was the literal baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learned-about-myself&quot;&gt;what I learned about myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this was the first summer of my life away from the comfort of family. I’d never known anything else. I had a roommate, of course, but given that he came home at 9PM every day and left for Seoul every weekend, I have to say that I was honorarily alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what I learned? &lt;em&gt;being alone isn’t bad at all, and it’s an almost necessary condition for introspection and appreciation of the world.&lt;/em&gt; note the difference between &lt;em&gt;being alone&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;feeling lonely&lt;/em&gt;. family and friends were always a Facetime call, a Facebook message, an Instagram comment away, but the physical loneliness urged me to venture out of my comfort zone. honestly, my time in Korea brought to me a surge of emotions I hadn’t felt ever since I first came to MIT. at that time, too, I left behind the comfort of friends and family. two years later, I’ve fully adapted to Massachusetts and its winters, its atmosphere. no doubt I’d adjust similarly if I stayed in Korea for longer than three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from here on, I’m going to respect my personal time. I’m going to seek out more and more opportunities to be away from the bustle of the city, to sit and think about my life, to give thanks for the blessings I’ve received which so many others so desperately desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-note-future-interns&quot;&gt;a note: future interns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for those looking for a MISTI experience in Korea, I have a few tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;do not slack off in Korean class.&lt;/em&gt; every vocabulary word and every grammatical structure needs to be a part of you. live and breathe the language. pay attention to every phrase/sentence you hear in your songs and dramas. conversational Korean, to be sure, is very different from formally taught Korean, but that doesn’t give you an excuse to slack off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if your living accommodations aren’t furnished, prepare to make a trip to Daiso for cheap supplies. go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://emart.ssg.com/main.ssg&quot;&gt;e-mart&lt;/a&gt; for a cheap, no-brand office chair (I got mine for 44,000₩).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;buy bug spray and sunscreen. the humidity and heat were almost enough to kill me most days. it gets a bit better on rainy days, but for the most part, expect to be &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read up on Korean public transportation and how it works ahead of time. I learned more than a week in, and it didn’t help that I was late. when you return to the States, you’ll probably miss Korean public transportation for the rest of your life. I sure do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seoul is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the only city in which one can have fun. explore the nooks and crannies of your assigned city. breathe in the fresh air. go for a hike. walk the markets. take the bus at night in silence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t be shy! modern-generation Koreans love to interact with foreigners and gain perspective for themselves. arguably, my best friends this summer were the three other interns (all natives) in my lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are more, but they slip my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;unforgettable&quot;&gt;unforgettable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll never forget the Buddhist temple retreat. it wasn’t so much the activities, but the exposure to nature that made me happy and at peace with myself. reuniting with the other interns and Matt Burt and Professor Jeong were amongst the highlights of the summer, to be honest, and I loved the hike we did together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that’s one for the books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;until next time, Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 01:09:47 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/reflections/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/reflections/</guid>
        
        <category>Korea</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>이천도예, 신촌물총축제 // arts &amp; water</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;this weekend was marked by a deep appreciation for the dying arts and a return to childhood fun I hadn’t experienced in years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pottery in 이천&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sponsored by the MISTI-Korea program, the other MIT interns and I met up in 서울 with our program director, Matt Burt, to visit a nearby city, 이천, renowned for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ceramic.or.kr/korean/&quot;&gt;its rich history in ceramics&lt;/a&gt;. the city &lt;em&gt;seemed&lt;/em&gt; very rural, but after living in Korea for almost two months, I don’t think I’d deem it officially “rural”, given the modern standards of living here. the setting reminded me of Vietnam, crop fields and uneven land encroaching humble homes and rustic factories. the homes’ interiors? stark contrast. modern living, equipped with HDTVs, laundry machines, spray toilets—luxuries one wouldn’t attribute to traditional rural homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;upon being told by our guide that 900-1300 degrees Celsius is the golden standard for firing, I froze in my tracks. I’d known what absolute zero was, of course, but the thought of clay being fired up to over 2000 degrees Fahrenheit made me question for the first time whether an absolute max exists or not. heck, you’d probably be dead within 10 seconds of stepping foot in a kiln of that heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we were taken to a museum of sorts, complete with the richest, most treasured pieces known to Korea. we’re talking pieces gorgeous and antique enough to be featured at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metmuseum.org&quot;&gt;the Met&lt;/a&gt;. each piece was priced from roughly 5,000,000 to 15,000,000KRW. &lt;em&gt;that’s a lot of money&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;our next stop was the home of a potter with 41 years of experience. I was blown away by the steadiness of his hands, the careful strokes he made as he drew two sparrows perched upon a branch with nothing but four colors and his imagination. it was there that I went behind the wheel for the first time—with foot on the pedal, hands on the mound, I conquered. not bad for a first-timer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at noon, we went for lunch together, with plentiful servings and esoteric side dishes (반찬). a store next to the restaurant offered hundreds of pottery pieces, but upon closer inspection, I realized that these were nothing more than manufactured souvenirs, and thus, I concluded my search for something to bring home (or so I thought).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;half the day was already over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we visited two more potters after lunch, but these weren’t just any random guys: they were two of the 21 &lt;em&gt;Masterhands&lt;/em&gt; in all of Korea. what’s a Masterhand? &lt;a href=&quot;http://boyeok.koreasme.com/en/sub2.html&quot;&gt;someone who’s devoted more than 20 years and contributed significant meaning to their art&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t catch their names, but they were spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the first focuses on technique and style from the 고려 dynasty, an era before the 조선 dynasty. celadon is his specialty, and the intricacy of his designs blew me away. we watched a documentary detailing the process from start to finish, from the making of the clay to the glazing and firing of the created shape. it’s amazing how dedicated he is. even after spending hours and hours on a piece, the slightest observable flaw prompts him to break his work with a hammer. it’s painful to watch such beautiful art crumble, but who am I to gauge a piece the beauty of which only its creator knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the second focuses on technique and style from the 조선 dynasty, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseon_white_porcelain&quot;&gt;a time when white porcelain was most praised and respected&lt;/a&gt;. his work doesn’t have the geometric intricacy of the first, but the free-hand drawings and colors he produces are impeccable. he works with a palette of colors produced from mixing cobalt, gold, copper, and iron. they’re all various shades of red before firing, which gives a monochromatic prerender of sorts. after firing, the colors are full, vibrant, and beautiful. when asked about how he visualizes the outcome from only red, we were told that &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt; was all it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s amazing. this art form has been embedded so deep into their hearts and minds such that it’s practically a functional aspect of their lives, no different from breathing or seeing. I’ve developed a huge admiration for all that potters do, and it’s a relief that in this modern age, the arts still live on through these passionate people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;water gun mayhem at 신촌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning. the dawn breaks, the skies turn cloudy, and my phone wakes me up. I shower and walk to church. it’s a relatively lax morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as I’m walking the edge of 한강, Jasmine texts me and asks if I want to meet up for lunch. at this point, I’m pretty tired, but I go anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we meet up at 이화대학교 and treat ourselves to shrimp udon and fried ramen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;then, the fun begins.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we walked to 신촌, where every year, a watergun festival is held. thousands gather for the music, the mayhem, and the water. we bought &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; water guns for 10,000KRW each and began our conquest on the streets. I won’t elaborate much, but I will say this: remember your youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;unfortunately, my camera suffered water damage. I’m still unsure about its condition, but it refuses to start up properly. lesson learned: weatherproof does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean waterproof.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:09:47 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/second-weekend-in-seoul/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/second-weekend-in-seoul/</guid>
        
        <category>Korea</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>덕과 도리 // virtue and duty</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in our world, seasons come and go. with fall comes happiness, as the advent of maple leaves and warm hues brings about a paradoxical hope one wouldn’t regularly associate with fall’s withering nature. winter, then, is the saddest season, for its harsh cold and relentless demands take a heavy toll on anybody with enough will to bear it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;there’s something more beyond our world. the universe too has seasons. we live now in a fiery world, a world that flaunts its gems: greed, money, comfort. what comes after?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to focus this one on a recent turn of events, one that’s progressed to a point others might rightfully call something out of a Korean drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that woman? 황성진? I couldn’t have been more wrong about her—she’s a complete angel. she was never out to get me, and I dare say I’m even developing the tiniest semblance of a crush. that’s obviously unfeasible, of course, so let’s get to the &lt;em&gt;meat&lt;/em&gt; of this whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with some assistance from my roommate, 치호, I decided that I’d meet this woman again and see what she’d say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trusted her, and we entered this locked building, going up to the fourth floor alone together. the place seemed legit enough, but I was still ready to haul ass out of there at any moment. veins popping, blood rushing, eyes watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instead, she put on a beautiful 한복 and set up all this elaborate food for what was to be 효도, a ceremony for one’s ancestors—namely mine. she asked me for my personal information—birthday, parent’s birthdays, their names, when I’d return to the US—it suddenly felt strange again. I lied completely, but in hindsight, I wish I’d trusted her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;she wrote this info on several pieces of real parchment with various Chinese characters all over them. we knelt down and bowed at the altar, and as she burnt those pieces of parchment, she chanted something hauntingly beautiful, melodically. that ceremony was meant as a sendoff to my ancestors who had died unjustly and were still wandering this earth. again, not something I seriously believe in, but I appreciated the ceremony, and wish I’d told the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;it was all smooth sailing from there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we’ve been meeting regularly since then, maybe twice or thrice a week, to talk about philosophy, life in South Korea, and the attitudes of modern urbanites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the vocabulary through which she conducts our meetings is a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; to take in, but I’ve learned so much. 욕심, 불세상, 지옥, 천국, 현재, and so many others have flooded my mind. you see that prologue up there? that’s only a fraction of what we’ve talked about so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the next time we meet—this Thursday (7/27)—will involve Buddhist prayer. I’m not quite sure what that entails, but we’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this was one of my goals for the summer abroad: to immerse myself culturally and absorb as many different worldviews as I can possibly manage. it’s working out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 01:09:47 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/seongjin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/seongjin/</guid>
        
        <category>Korea</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>설마... // strangers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;a lot has been happening recently. Korea's an interesting place, and only now do I realize that there's so much to be learned. the proper adage for the events that transgressed within the last two hours:&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;never trust a stranger&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;(especially abroad).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it's been a while since I last wrote an entry, but today's events&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;must&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;be recorded in some form. I made my way to 은행동 by taking the train to 중앙로, as always. ate 떡볶이 at a street stand, treated myself to affogato-flavored 빙수, and bought some skincare products from Nature Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;just as I'm about to cross the street and enter the subway station to head home,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;this woman ahead of me turns around and stares intently into my eyes.&lt;/em&gt; it was creepy as hell (she was very pretty, though... hahaha).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&quot;저, 혹시 지금 시간이 있으세요?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&quot;네... 근데 제가 한국 사람이 아닌데요.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&quot;아, 한국말 잘해요. 저는 'study people' 사람이에요. 20분만은 필요해요.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;she was accompanied by this man who just conveniently had a translation app on hand. looking back, I believe they were definitely prepared well ahead of time. I was just another &quot;easy, naive-looking target&quot;. I figured:&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;okay, 20 minutes for a study about cultural experiences isn't bad at all. broaden your worldviews, yeah?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;little did I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;they wanted me to buy them both coffee... it was expensive, too. I had the wits to buy only one, but I should've gotten nothing at all&amp;mdash;if&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;you&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;want to interview&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, why don't you buy the coffee? it was fishy from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apparently, the woman's a kindergarten teacher who's 26 years old. her name is 황성진. the other guy? well, he never mentioned a single thing about himself, and when I asked him about his occupation, he said it had something to do with &quot;the holy order&quot;. w h a t ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;she started off with this philosophical discussion about Korean culture and the necessity for filial loyalty, or 효도, as they translated for me. it's some ancient Korean doctrine that has its roots in Confucianism. she drew a tree, labeling the roots as &quot;ancestors&quot;, the body as &quot;family&quot;, and the head as &quot;you&quot; (or &quot;me&quot;, whatever the point of view is), subsequently asking me which was most important to me. response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&quot;저한테 가적은 제일 중요해요. 제 부모님은 저를 많이 사랑해서 복 많이 받은 사람이에요.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I respected everything she had to say, and was pretty hyped about how the rest of this &quot;study&quot;/interview would go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then they started getting weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;they kept spewing this nonsense about my needing to go perform filial rites at some temple alone with them. something felt really, really off. by that time, about maybe 35 minutes had passed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;huh, interesting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;naturally, I told them no matter how much they tried to convince me, there was no way that I'd follow some strangers I'd only just met somewhere. what's even more funny is that they tried to dismiss my ardent Catholicism. his translation app (which wasn't Google's) had this message (verbatim 90%, give or take a few): &quot;You won't success for you or ancestors if you pray.&quot; like what? I respect Confucianism and all, but goodness, let me breathe with my own faith. I asked them why they were trying&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;so hard&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;to convince me even after 40-50 minutes had passed, and all he had to say was: &lt;em&gt;it's fate&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;we have a connection with you&lt;/em&gt;. I was about ready to burst with tears at that point. who's naive enough to fall for that?&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;this is your only chance to honor your relatives. it's your only, only chance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;I thus called a friend from Seoul, and he promptly told me never to trust those kinds of people. I knew something felt off. I left right away, but in the rare possibility that they might just be some zealous, religious people (&lt;em&gt;highly unlikely...)&lt;/em&gt;, I apologized for wasting their time, if I did at all. I didn't apologize for saying the Korean equivalent of &quot;bullshit&quot; in response to their claiming&amp;nbsp;that our meeting was fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so, some reflections: they were either traffickers or scammers targeting naive-looking people. I'm definitely not a fool, so it's clear their scheme didn't work on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;regarding the philosophical side of things: whether or not their scheme was grounded in Confucianism and Korean culture, I learned a lot&amp;mdash;I don't necessarily agree with all of it. who says there's only one chance in your life to pay respects to your elders? hell, I pray to God every Sunday for my wellbeing, that of my family, that of my friends, that of the world. and this thing about fate? sorry, but I make my own decisions, and if you think that we have some kind of special connection, hate to break it to ya, but life ain't a Korean drama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did give her a prank call back on Kakaotalk once I returned home, offering to sing for her. what a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you learn new things all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 01:09:47 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/scam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/scam/</guid>
        
        <category>Korea</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>첫 주말 // first weekend</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;cheers to the first weekend spent in South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, 6/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;people told me that 대전 would be boring, but it really isn't. I don't believe&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;anywhere&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;is boring if one just takes the opportunities lying around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my first stop on the itinerary Saturday afternoon? 뿌리공원, a peaceful park located at the very bottom of 대전. I felt a sense of inner harmony, one I hadn't felt in so long, when I was there. perhaps it was the change of scenery&amp;mdash;where in the United States do you find a park on the outskirts of the city, neighboring beautiful, domineering mountains and rivers? I think this description generalizes well to Asia. the beauty of our mountainscapes and rivers is unrivaled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to take a trip on the self-propelling duck boat. it felt great to go on the river by myself. facetimed mom, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I really hadn't felt that peaceful in such a long time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;afterwards, I headed to 우암사적공원, a history park that was apparently the grounds for some famous Korean general or leader during the 조선 Dynasty. what do you know? the place was closed, and it was then that I realized that I irrevocably screwed myself over for the day by straying so far from 누리관. I was probably more than 7 miles away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then again, does it really matter when amazing photo ops are involved? I got some amazing shots, and it's true&amp;mdash;these pictures speak more than this b&amp;amp;w text I'm typing now. afterwards, stopped by Lotte Mart and got 2.7L of various juices for&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;cheap&lt;/em&gt;. there was also a 떢볶이 deal, 1,500KRW for one serving.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;is it obvious that I ordered two servings? nothing beats&amp;nbsp;떢볶이.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I returned home and got my first taste of the actual subway system. one word. amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, 6/11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;I slept in. did some quick shopping around the Golfzon area, trying to further understand the process of how markets work around here. I was dismayed at just how expensive Starbucks is in this country. a java bean frappucino costs nearly $3 more for the base size, and that's quite a leap. consumerism at its finest, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;yes, I gave in. I visited BHC, a popular chicken franchise in Korea that's been around since 2013. a waitress greeted me, and later asked for my contact information. I was surprised when she told me that she also wasn't Korean; I'm too used to having a native accent that when I hear others with one, I forget to consider that they might be foreigners as well. numberless, I gave her my Kakaotalk instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;then church, the last milestone of the day. my first Korean mass! I understood little of the sermon, but some deduction skills led to this recap: he was talking about the Trinity and why for some people, it's so difficult to comprehend. something about grabbing on to the hand of the Lord, since we'll never know what the future has in store for us, whether that's an hour, a week, a year from now. powerful stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;tep sxt-align: left;&quot;&gt;I went home, and by that time, Chiho had returned. some TV, and sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 01:09:47 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/first-weekend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/first-weekend/</guid>
        
        <category>Korea</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
