<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://longnguyen1997.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 13:28:09 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 13:28:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>full circle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;last day of class, and a lot of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;why is Stata’s design centered around blue and tan? is that a complementary pair?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;why do I deserve a recitation instructor like Mark Stuart Day? &lt;em&gt;my usual example of overdoing it was my dissertation committee; it consisted of the scariest—Barbara Liskov, who went on to win the Turing award, and Butler Lampson, who also won the Turing award, and so on… it’s all good until the dream breaks and you don’t graduate. relatives and friends attending my recitation were sent to our child’s baptism instead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;why do I care about people? how is it noticeable enough to the point that every one of the students in my recitations pointed it out when I asked for feedback? is that an unconscious thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think these questions have satisfying answers; they probe pretty deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also, things really came full circle. I passed on Mark’s decades-long experiential advice to my own students less than an hour later, as if I’d been in his shoes. they, in turn, may pass that on further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John approached me after recitation ended. wow, so Latter-day Saints have stricter, more conservative beliefs than us Catholics? wasn’t aware of that. or much else, for that matter. wonder if he’d corrected the woman who wrongly assumed that his work in quantum physics was enough justification for derailing religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;seems like everything integrates into a circle. not in the numerical sense—seems like all of life is a circle. the Lord comes and goes, the Lord comes and goes again. people are born, people die. classes diverge, classes converge. seasons come, seasons go. friends arrive, friends depart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is that generalization, or is it fact?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 12:09:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/full-circle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/full-circle/</guid>
        
        <category>MIT</category>
        
        <category>reflections</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>biology revisited</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;being conducive to biology can be interpreted in a lot of ways. are you someone who just wants to study life sciences for a degree? maybe you’re someone who aspires to be a doctor, saving lives here and there. maybe you’re just someone who appreciates the complex, enigmatic nature of life itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at one point, I was all three. an old-timer who used his high school stem cell research as an excuse to follow a biology/bioengineering degree. a firm believer in the importance of the world and the lives of everyone in it. a student who wanted to delve deeper, who could never get enough of the mysterious edge cases that defy textbook principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m no longer all three. after all, it took me 2.5 years before finally deciding to take my biology requirement here, something I’d meant to complete freshman spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;revisiting biology after four years, my emotions haven’t really changed. the fervor I had throughout the semester really does surprise me—always raising my hand in recitation, always asking about potential situations that could break a problem presented. the scientist rose once more. &lt;em&gt;if we assume that computer science isn’t a science.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there are only so many things one can do in life. classical guitar, videogames, novels, friends, food, relaxation, sleep, code, papers… the list goes on and on. where would life be had I stuck to biology?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ah, Lord, I suppose only you know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 12:15:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/biology_revisited/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/biology_revisited/</guid>
        
        <category>reflections</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>last staff meeting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;the Jackson Room. a distant, fourth-floor meeting space in the deepest reaches of Building 38.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see the Excel spreadsheet before me, a mass of numbers upon numbers indiscernible to the naked eye unless observed diligently within several centimeters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see absences, recovered recitations, late arrivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I see special cases from Student Support Services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this time of the year can be rough for all of us. I’m blessed to have some time off this week, but I’m fully aware that this is probably a trough in my sinusoidal wave. MIT isn’t trivial, and this last staff meeting served as a brutal reminder of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;having never relied on Mental Health or Student Support Services these three years, I think I’m extremely blessed to have the fortitude and determination that I do. partly attributed to my nurture, mostly attributed to my nature. the fact that so many cases occur that we, as staff, have to deliberate for minutes for each student makes it clear that I’m not the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that I can be the norm. it’s wishful thinking. it’s foolish faith. but it’s a feeling that those like me share for the MIT community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nobody should have to jump. nobody should have to cry over numbers. nobody should have to worry about a condition that takes them out of the running for a presentation that yields 15% of their final grade that they absolutely cannot make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as both an objective staff member and an emotional human being, I’m at a crossroads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on to the next semester. on to more students. on to more grading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 12:09:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/staffmeeting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/staffmeeting/</guid>
        
        <category>MIT</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>junior year</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;junior year’s about to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a week left of the massive pollen influx destroying my immune system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a week left of dragging my feet through classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned a lot this year, from life more so than from school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;forged new connections, rekindled old ones; all in all, I’ve focused myself a lot more on my human side. so much more writing than coding. technical material that drew me in before still does, to some degree, but I’ve found more enjoyment in the little things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;going out to dinner alone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;listening to Mendelssohn, Tárrega, Chopin, and Barrios on repeat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dedicating 2 hours a day towards classical guitar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;setting up half-hour catchups with friends old and new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there’s a lot more to be said, but I’ll summarize this one succintly: &lt;em&gt;love and life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;be careful in doing what you do. don’t get caught up in the details. see the bigger picture in &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;. realize the necessity of &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;. love your friends, your neighbors, your families, yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:09:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/junioryear/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/junioryear/</guid>
        
        <category>MIT</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>my time in Korea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;warning: this is a particularly long post. activate your browser’s Reading Mode (if it has one) for a more pleasant time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity&quot;&gt;opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this summer, I had the pleasure of working at the Electronics &amp;amp; Telecommunications Institute of Korea (ETRI, or 한국전자통신연구원 in Korean), courtesy of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://misti.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;MIT International Science and Technology Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. working down the hierarchy, we go from ETRI to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etri.re.kr/eng/sub6/sub6_01020102.etri;jsessionid=061E58886E8372E2F7F340AC2801A1A5?departCode=101&amp;amp;departInfoCode=191&quot;&gt;Software Contents Research Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, from there to the Intelligent Robotics Research Division, from there to the Human-Machine Interaction Research Group, and from there to my desk. at the head of the HMI Research Group is 박재홍, and my mentor for the summer was 윤영우. there really should be honorifics, but for the sake of blogging, let’s just consider names as names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project&quot;&gt;project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as part of the HMI Research Group (which I will defer to HMIRG henceforth), my responsibility as an intern was to investigate &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis&quot;&gt;sentiment analysis&lt;/a&gt; and natural behavior in physical robotics. I was given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ald.softbankrobotics.com/en/robots/nao&quot;&gt;NAO robot&lt;/a&gt; to work with. the current state of robotics movement leaves much to be desired—we don’t have many robots that can actually generate realistic gestures in realtime as they speak. instead, what many manufacturers opt for are predefined gestures replicated from short video clips—in NAO’s case, coded by hand in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XML&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;XML&lt;/code&gt; format&lt;/a&gt;. these gestures are rather repetitive and predictable. do humans move their head with identical spatial, temporal parameters every time they express agreement to something? didn’t think so! by using machine learning, statistics (which itself is a crucial part of ML), and natural language processing, we can train robots to better respond in an organic way during real interactions with real people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;having come in with &lt;em&gt;zero&lt;/em&gt; NLP/ML experience, I found myself daunted during the initial stages. I quickly caught up on theory, thanks to MIT’s 6.036 Spring 2015 notes, acquainting myself with the ML library &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn&lt;/code&gt; and the NLP libraries &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;spaCy&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nltk&lt;/code&gt;. I learned quite a lot, and though there were some dull moments during the project that involved tedious tasks like collecting robot sensor data, I loved doing what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language-barrier-the-greatest-challenge&quot;&gt;language barrier: the greatest challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I speak for a lot of people when I say that the biggest problem living and working in Korea was the language barrier. despite having studied Korean for two years at MIT, I found myself lost the moment I set foot in Korea. four semesters—not quite enough. I now realize that I haven’t even crossed the barrier between &lt;em&gt;beginning&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;comfortable&lt;/em&gt; yet. a big help was that fact that the Korean, Japanese, and Vietnamese languages are heavily Sinicized (influenced by Chinese culture). over 60% of these languages are derived from Chinese characters; in my case, Vietnamese derives from Hán tự, while Korean derives from 한자. so many words are the same, with only minute differences in pronunciation. this made a lot of new vocabulary words pretty trivial and engrained the moment I saw them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bottom line: I was required to adapt. I chose Daejeon over Seoul for complete immersion. I think I can count on one hand the number of times I saw foreigners in Daejeon during my almost-3-month stay. signs in Korean were everywhere, and my ears were, at any given moment, ready to burst from the amount of information cramming itself into their canals. it speaks volumes that my reading speed is at least three times as fast as it was before I arrived (and that’s after two years of studying the language formally). I can now think of what to say next as my brain quickly processes Korean grammar rules and strings together phrases accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can expose yourself to any language for years and years through formal courses and television, but your rate of growth is &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much more pronounced when you’re actually in an environment that allows breathing room for &lt;em&gt;only that language&lt;/em&gt;. for those of you looking to come to South Korea, do yourself a favor and don’t rely on your English to get you around. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work-culture-in-a-foreign-country&quot;&gt;work culture in a foreign country&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because I was at a research institute, I can’t say for certain that my experience accurately describes that of those in industry. for the most part, it’s pretty similar to the US, with a few differences. first, you’re expected to come in at 9:00, leaving at 18:00 with an hour-long lunch break. Koreans are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; punctual and work-oriented: one of the senior researchers in my lab lives about a $25 taxi ride away, yet was always at his desk by around 8:30. as far as I know, most people in the Bay Area working at software companies are free to come around 10-11 and leave pretty early in the afternoon, granted their work is solid. definitely a difference. second, greetings and etiquette are emphasized more heavily in Korea. once, one of the project leaders scolded me for not saying hello to every member of the lab when I came in. it was terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we also practiced the standard Korean tradition of 회식 (hweh-shik), which involves nights of debauchery with dozens of beer bottles and comfortable conversation in the company of one’s colleagues. I’m a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good drinker, so this was no problem, and more importantly, these nights reminded me a lot of good times back in Cambridge with my friends. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/news/biz/2016/04/328_139616.html&quot;&gt;Korea being a workaholic country&lt;/a&gt; is no joke, but it’s traditions like these that, understandably, sway your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;had I stayed in the US for an internship, I wouldn’t have grown so much. all summer, work felt secondary next to the cultural nuances, the unpredictable weather that is the annual 장마, the language exchanges during which I spoke in broken Korean and the other interns replied in broken English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also, did I mention that I was the youngest in the lab by at least four years to everyone else? I was the literal baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learned-about-myself&quot;&gt;what I learned about myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this was the first summer of my life away from the comfort of family. I’d never known anything else. I had a roommate, of course, but given that he came home at 9PM every day and left for Seoul every weekend, I have to say that I was honorarily alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what I learned? &lt;em&gt;being alone isn’t bad at all, and it’s an almost necessary condition for introspection and appreciation of the world.&lt;/em&gt; note the difference between &lt;em&gt;being alone&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;feeling lonely&lt;/em&gt;. family and friends were always a Facetime call, a Facebook message, an Instagram comment away, but the physical loneliness urged me to venture out of my comfort zone. honestly, my time in Korea brought to me a surge of emotions I hadn’t felt ever since I first came to MIT. at that time, too, I left behind the comfort of friends and family. two years later, I’ve fully adapted to Massachusetts and its winters, its atmosphere. no doubt I’d adjust similarly if I stayed in Korea for longer than three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from here on, I’m going to respect my personal time. I’m going to seek out more and more opportunities to be away from the bustle of the city, to sit and think about my life, to give thanks for the blessings I’ve received which so many others so desperately desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-note-future-interns&quot;&gt;a note: future interns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for those looking for a MISTI experience in Korea, I have a few tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;do not slack off in Korean class.&lt;/em&gt; every vocabulary word and every grammatical structure needs to be a part of you. live and breathe the language. pay attention to every phrase/sentence you hear in your songs and dramas. conversational Korean, to be sure, is very different from formally taught Korean, but that doesn’t give you an excuse to slack off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if your living accommodations aren’t furnished, prepare to make a trip to Daiso for cheap supplies. go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://emart.ssg.com/main.ssg&quot;&gt;e-mart&lt;/a&gt; for a cheap, no-brand office chair (I got mine for 44,000₩).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;buy bug spray and sunscreen. the humidity and heat were almost enough to kill me most days. it gets a bit better on rainy days, but for the most part, expect to be &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read up on Korean public transportation and how it works ahead of time. I learned more than a week in, and it didn’t help that I was late. when you return to the States, you’ll probably miss Korean public transportation for the rest of your life. I sure do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seoul is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the only city in which one can have fun. explore the nooks and crannies of your assigned city. breathe in the fresh air. go for a hike. walk the markets. take the bus at night in silence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t be shy! modern-generation Koreans love to interact with foreigners and gain perspective for themselves. arguably, my best friends this summer were the three other interns (all natives) in my lab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are more, but they slip my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;unforgettable&quot;&gt;unforgettable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll never forget the Buddhist temple retreat. it wasn’t so much the activities, but the exposure to nature that made me happy and at peace with myself. reuniting with the other interns and Matt Burt and Professor Jeong were amongst the highlights of the summer, to be honest, and I loved the hike we did together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that’s one for the books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;until next time, Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 12:09:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/reflections/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://longnguyen1997.github.io/posts/reflections/</guid>
        
        <category>Korea</category>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
